A Guide to the Virginia Academy of Science Records, 1920-2005
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
- Box 13, 1972-1975 (Box 13)
  - Major W. Catesby Jones Award--Correspondence--S. Ragone, 1973-1974
  - Russell J. Rowlett, Jr. Award (VJAS)--Correspondence--Harshbarger, 1973-1974
  - Officers and Committees, 1973-1974
  - Council--Correspondence--Harshbarger, 1973-1974
  - Long Range Planning Committee--Correspondence and minutes--Ulrich and Wisman, 1973-1974
  - Publications Committee--Correspondence and reports, 1973-1974
  - Virginia Museum of Science--Correspondence--A. W. Burke, 1973-1974
  - Virginia Museum of Science--Correspondence--Wisman, 1973-1974
  - Visiting Scientists Program--Report--Ulrich, 1973-1974
  - Requests for envelopes by sections, 1973-1974
  - Inauguration of President Frank Hereford, Jr. (University of Virginia President), 1974
  - Financial Statements--L. Guy Bennett, 1974
  - Taxes, 1974
  - Mailing list changes, 1974
  - Social Security Tax Refund, 1974
  - Bicentennial (VAS Ad Hoc Committee), 1974-1975
  - Vera Remsburg--Correspondence, 1974-1975
  - Miscellaneous Committees--Correspondence and reports--Long Range Planning Committee, Nation's Bicentennial Committee, Finance Committee, Flora Committee, and State Certification-Science Education, 1974-1975
  - Miscellaneous Sections--Reports--Environmental Science and Microbiology, 1974-1975
  - Agricultural Science Section--Correspondence and minutes, 1974-1975
  - Annual Meeting--Schedule of Responsibilities, 1974-1975
  - Annual Meeting--Report, 1974-1975
  - Archives--Correspondence, 1974-1975
  - Awards Committee--Correspondence--General, Major W. Catesby Jones Award, Russell J Rowlett, Jr. Award, and Ivey F. Lewis Award, 1974-1975
  - Awards--Fellows--Correspondence--Remsburg, 1974-1975
  - Bicentennial Committee--Correspondence, 1974-1975
  - By-laws and Constitution, 1974-1975
  - Community and Junior College Participation--Correspondence--Wisman, President, 1974-1975
  - Council--Correspondence and reports--Wisman, 1974-1975
  - Council--Minutes, 1974-1975
  - Council--Correspondence and minutes--Burke, 1974-1975
- Box 14, 1974-1976 (Box 14)
  - Council--Correspondence--Harshbarger, 1974-1975
  - Financial Reports, 1974-1975
  - Local Arrangements--Correspondence--Wisman, 1974-1975
  - Local Arrangements Committee--Final Report, 1974-1975
  - Membership Committee--Correspondence--Wisman, 1974-1975
  - State Water Control Board--Correspondence--Ad Hoc Advisory Committee, 1974-1975
  - Virginia Junior Academy of Science--Correspondence and reports, 1974-1975
  - Virginia Museum of Science--Correspondence--Wisman, 1974-1975
  - Visiting Scientists Program--Correspondence--Ulrich, 1974-1975
  - Visiting Scientists--Correspondence--Ulrich--High Schools, Junior Colleges, and Universities, 1974-1975
  - Trust Committee--Correspondence and reports, 1974-1975
  - Financial Statements--L. Guy Bennett, 1975
  - Taxes, 1975
  - Fellow of VAS, 1975-1980
  - A. W. Burke, Jr.--Correspondence--President, 1975-1976
  - Vera Remsburg--Correspondence, 1975-1976
  - Officers, 1975-1976
  - Agricultural Science Section--Correspondence, minutes, and abstracts, 1975-1976
  - Annual Meeting, Local Arrangements, and Schedule of Responsibilities--Correspondence--Burke, 1975-1976
  - Annual Meeting--Report, 1975-1976
  - Archives--Correspondence, 1975-1976
  - Awards Committee--Correspondence--Burke, 1975-1976
  - Fellow--Correspondence--Remsburg, 1975-1976
  - Negus Memorial Lec.--Correspondence, 1975-1976
  - Bicentennial (national)--Correspondence--D. C. Bliss, 1975-1976
  - Botany Section--Minutes, 1975-1976
  - Business Relations Committee--Correspondence--Burke, 1975-1976
  - By-laws and Constitution--Correspondence--Burke and Wisman, 1975-1976
  - Community Colleges and Universities--Correspondence and lists, 1975-1976
  - Council--Minutes, 1975-1976
  - Finance Committee--Correspondence and Budget Reports--Burke, 1975-1976
  - Flora Committee--Correspondence--Burke, 1975-1976
  - Long Range Planning Committee--Correspondence, 1975-1976
  - Membership Committee--Correspondence--Burke and Ulrich, 1975-1976
  - National Science Foundation--Correspondence--Burke, 1975-1976
  - Nominating Committee--Correspondence, 1975-1976
  - Publications Committee--Correspondence--Burke and Wisman, 1975-1976
  - Publications Committee--Correspondence--Burke, Dismal Swamp, 1975-1976
  - Research Committee--Correspondence--Wisman, 1975-1976
  - Virginia Journal of Science--Correspondence--West, 1975-1976
  - Science Education Committee and Ad Hoc--Correspondence and Reports--Burke, 1975-1976
  - Virginia Museum of Science--Correspondence--Burke, 1975-1976
  - Visiting Scientists Program--Correspondence--Ulrich, 1975-1976
- Box 15, 1975-1978 (Box 15)
  - Flora Committee, 1975-1977
  - Awards, 1975-1977
  - Budget for Research Committee, 1975-1979, 1989
  - Financial Statements--Charles M. Terry & Co., 1976
  - Constitution, 1976
  - Mailing list changes, 1976
  - Taxes, 1976
  - Agricultural Science Section--Correspondence, 1976-1977
  - Annual Meeting--Reports--Site Visit Report, 1976-1977
  - Academy Assembly and Academy Conference--Minutes and reports, 1976-1977
  - Awards Committee--Correspondence--Nominations for Fellows, 1976-1977
  - Botany Section--Minutes, 1976-1977
  - Council--Minutes, 1976-1977
  - Council--Correspondence, Minutes and Reports, 1976-1977
  - National Science Foundation--Correspondence--Burke, 1976-1977
  - Annual program--Correspondence--Ulrich, 1976-1977
  - Visiting Scientists Program--Correspondence--Ulrich, 1976-1977
  - Reports on Examination, 1976-1977
  - Directory, 1976-1977
  - Minutes and reports of the Virginia Museum of Science, 1976-1980
  - Minutes of Fellows of VAS Annual Meetings, 1976-1991
  - Financial Statements--Charles M. Terry & Co., 1977
  - Mailing list changes, 1977
  - S. G. Bradley--Correspondence--Secretary, 1977-1978
  - D. V. Ulrich--Correspondence--President-elect, 1977-1978
  - Agricultural Science Section--Correspondence, Minutes, and Abstracts, 1977-1978
  - Annual Meeting--Correspondence--Program, Poster Session, and Report, 1977-1978
  - Awards Committee--Correspondence, 1977-1978
  - Council--Minutes, 1977-1978
  - Virginia Journal of Science--Correspondence--Remsburg, 1977-1978
- Box 16, 1977-1980 (Box 16)
  - Visiting Scientists Program--Reports--Ulrich, 1977-1978
  - Virginia Journal of Science, 1977-1981
  - Financial Statements, 1978
  - Mailing list changes, 1978
  - Harshbarger--Correspondence, 1978-1979
  - Remsburg--Correspondence--President-elect, 1978-1979
  - Ulrich--Correspondence--President, 1978-1979
  - Agricultural Science Section--Correspondence--Knight, 1978-1979
  - Annual Meeting (1981)--Correspondence--Ulrich, 1978-1979
  - Annual Meeting Program (1979)--Correspondence--Ulrich, 1978-1979
  - Awards Committee--Correspondence, 1978-1979
  - Botany Section and Flora Committee--Correspondence and reports--M. K. Roane and Ulrich, 1978-1979
  - Council--Correspondence, minutes and reports, 1978-1979
  - Finance Committee--Correspondence--Ulrich, 1978-1979
  - Fund Raising Committee--Correspondence--Ulrich, 1978-1979
  - Membership--Correspondence--Ulrich, 1978-1979
  - National Youth Science Club--Correspondence--Ulrich, 1978-1979
  - Publications Committee--Correspondence--Ulrich, 1978-1979
  - Science Education Committee--Correspondence, 1978-1979
  - Virginia Journal of Science--Correspondence--Ulrich and Remsburg, 1978-1979
  - Virginia Junior Academy of Science--Correspondence--Ulrich, 1978-1979
  - Visiting Scientists Program--Correspondence--Ulrich, 1978-1979
  - Council of Executive Committee Management, 1978-1979
  - Newspaper clippings on Evolution, 1978-1981
  - Financial Statements--Charles M. Terry & Co., 1979
  - Mailing list changes, 1979
  - Officers and Committees, 1979-1980
  - Vera Remsburg--Correspondence--President, 1979-1980
  - President Remsburg’s Council Plan Book, 1979-1980
  - Agricultural Science Section--Correspondence--J. E. Roberts, Sr., 1979-1980
  - Annual Meeting--Reports--Remsburg, 1979-1980
  - Annual Banquet--Correspondence and photographs--Remsburg, 1979-1980
  - Botany Section and Flora Committee--Reports--M. K. Roane, 1979-1980
  - Council--Minutes--Remsburg, 1979-1980
- Box 17, 1979-1982 (Box 17)
  - Council--Minutes--Remsburg, 1979-1980
  - Membership--Mailing list--Ulrich, 1979-1980
  - J. I. Good--Paper, 1979-1980
  - Virginia Journal of Science--Correspondence--Remsburg, 1979-1980
  - Minutes of Annual Meeting at University of Virginia, 1979-1980
  - Archives--VAS Ad Hoc Committee, 1979-1982, 1984
  - Financial Statements, 1980
  - Mailing list changes, 1980
  - Astronomy, Math, and Physics--Report "1923-1981: Officers and Places of Meetings"--D. R. Carpenter, 1980-1981
  - Botany Section and Flora Committee--Correspondence--M. K. Roane, 1980-1981
  - Agricultural Science Section--Minutes, 1980-1981
  - Council--Minutes and reports, 1980-1981
  - Membership--Mailing list--Ulrich, 1980-1981
  - Visiting Scientists Program--Report, 1980-1981
  - Thompson--Paper--"Promoting Science at the Grass Root Level," 1980-1981
  - Miscellaneous documents from VAS president-elect Don Cochran, 1980-1981
  - The National Association of Biology Teachers--Notes on evolution, 1981
  - VAS Committee Appointments, 1981
  - Copy of the Annual Program, 1981
  - Financial Statements, 1981
  - Mailing list changes, 1981
  - Miscellaneous Committees--Reports--Awards Committee, Membership Committee, Nominations Committee, Research Committee, and Science Advisory Committee, 1981-1982
  - Annual Meeting--Schedule of Responsibilities and arrangements, 1981-1982
  - Council--Minutes and reports, 1981-1982
  - Evolution Committee--Clippings--Ad Hoc Committee, 1981-1982
  - Membership--Mailing lists--Ulrich, 1981-1982
  - Visiting Scientists Program--Reports, 1981-1982
- Box 18, 1981-1983 (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous reports, documents, and minutes of VAS President, 1981-1982
  - Miscellaneous reports, documents, and minutes of VAS President, 1981-1982
  - VAS notes on Evolution and Creation, 1981-1982
  - VAS notes on Evolution and Creation, 1981-1982
  - Repurchase agreements for VAS, 1981-1982
  - Financial Statements, 1982
  - Mailing list changes, 1982
  - Minutes of May 20-22 Annual Meeting, 1982
  - Official minutes of November 7 Council Meeting, 1982
  - Agricultural Science Section--Secretary’s materials, 1982
  - Local Arrangements Committee--Minutes from annual meeting 1982
  - Miscellaneous reports and minutes from VAS president, 1982-1983
  - Financial Reports, 1982-1984
  - Newspaper clippings on Evolution, 1982-1986
  - Financial Statements, 1983
  - Mailing list changes, 1983
  - Official minutes of March 5 Council Meeting, 1983
  - Minutes of the Annual Meeting at George Mason, 1983
  - Agricultural Science Section--Secretary’s Materials, 1983
  - Final report of the Local Arrangements Committee, 1983
- Box 19, 1983-1991 (Box 19)
  - General Report, Local Arrangements, and Annual Meeting, 1983-1984
  - Invoices and budget, 1984
  - Minutes of the fall meeting, 1984
  - Official minutes of the May 18 Council Meeting, 1984
  - Agricultural Science Section--Secretary’s Materials, 1984
  - New members and mailing list changes, 1984
  - General report of Local Arrangements Committee--VAS Annual Meeting, 1984
  - Committees, elections, council minutes, and guidelines, 1984-1985
  - Local Arrangements Committee Reports, 1985
  - Minutes and reports from the May 14-17 meeting at William & Mary, 1985
  - Financial Statements and budget, 1985
  - Council minutes, meeting reports, and committees, 1985-1986
  - Financial Reports, 1985-1988
  - Budget and Invoices paid, 1986
  - Miscellaneous minutes of meeting throughout the year, 1986
  - Final report of the Local Arrangements Committee--VAS Annual meeting at James Madison University, 1986
  - Committee on Nominations and Elections, 1986-1987
  - Fellows of VAS Money Funds, 1986-1990
  - Budget and Invoices paid, 1987
  - Minutes of the Executive Committee meeting, 1988
  - Invoices paid, 1988
  - Report of the VAS meeting at the University of Virginia, 1988
  - Committee on Nominations and Elections--Registration for Annual Meeting, 1988-1989
  - Invoices paid, 1989
  - Financial reports, 1989-1991
- Box 20, 1990-1997, n.d. (Box 20)
  - Series of Vegetation Maps of Islands of Virginia, 1990
  - Miscellaneous documents and registration, 1991-1992
  - VAS and VJAS Annual Meeting Report--University of Richmond, 1992
  - Miscellaneous documents on registration and elections, 1992-1993
  - Financial Reports, 1992-1993
  - Miscellaneous papers, 1993
  - Council minutes, reports, documents, and committees, 1993-1994
  - Pamphlet and mailings concerning VAS, 1994
  - Miscellaneous documents on registration for the annual meeting, 1995-1996
  - Miscellaneous information on registration, 1996-1997
  - "Martha Ann Kolita Roane, 1921-1996"--Contributed by C. W. Roane, 1997
  - VAS History--George W. Jeffers, n.d.
  - George Jeffers, n.d.
  - William G. Guy, n.d.
  - John C. Forbes, n.d.
  - Lloyd C. Bird, n.d.
  - Hiram R. Hanmer, n.d.
  - Doris Kuhlmann-Wilsdorf, n.d.
  - Sidney S. Negus, n.d.
  - Vera B. Remsburg, n.d.
  - Wortley Fuller Rudd (1877?-1950), n.d.
  - Ivey Lewis Foreman, n.d.
  - Allan T. Gwathmey--Virginia Institute for Scientific Research, n.d.
  - E. C. L. Miller--Personal Correspondence, includes ground glass experiments, n.d.
  - Mary Eugenia Kapp, n.d.
  - Franklin Dadmun Kizer, n.d.
  - Unidentified photograph and a photograph of Decker and Taylor, n.d.
  - "The History of Early Publications of the Virginia Academy of Science 1930-1962"--by Boyd Harshbarger, n.d.
  - "History of the Virginia Academy of Science" Chapter 1 and Appendices, n.d.
  - Miscellaneous VAS stationary, seals, award certificates, and membership cards, n.d.
  - Biology Section--Reports--West, n.d.
  - Clippings--Science and the South, n.d.
  - Clippings--State Museums, n.d.
  - Science in Virginia, n.d.
  - Academies of Science in the United States, n.d.
  - Single clippings of biographical material, n.d.
  - E. C. L. Miller--Biographical clippings, photographs, and lectures, n.d.
  - Clippings of the VAS--Histories of the VAS by Miller and Lewis, n.d.
  - Biographical clippings and photographs of more than one individual, n.d.
  - Jeffersonia: A Newsletter of Virginia Botany, n.d.
  - Jeffersonia: A Newsletter of Virginia Botany, n.d.
- Box 21, Publications, 1923-1966 (Box 21)
  - Proceedings of the Virginia Academy of Science, 1923-1965
    Scope and Content
    Issues run between 1923 and 1965. Proceedings were then bound with the Virginia Journal of Science in 1950. Please see issues of the Virginia Journal of Science for continuation of proceedings.
  - Virginia Journal of Science, 1940-1942
    - Vol. 1, no, 1, 4-8, 1940
    - Vol. 2, no. 1-3, 5, 7-8 with index, 1941
    - Vol. 3, no. 1-7, 1942
  - Virginia Journal of Science: New Series, 1950-1966
    - Vol. 1, no. 1-4 with index. Proceedings in no. 4, 1950
    - Vol. 2, no. 1-4 with index. Proceedings in no. 4, 1951
    - Vol. 3, no. 1-4 with index. Proceedings in no. 4, 1952
    - Vol. 4, no. 1-4 with index. Proceedings in no. 4, 1953
    - Vol. 5, no. 1-4 with index. Proceedings in no. 4, 1954
    - Vol. 6, no. 1-4 with index. Proceedings in no. 4, 1955
    - Vol. 7, no. 1-4 with index. Proceedings in no. 4, 1956
    - Vol. 8, no. 1-4 with index. Proceedings in no. 4, 1957
    - Vol. 9, no. 1-4 with index. Proceedings in no. 4, 1958
    - Vol. 10, no. 1-4 with index. Proceedings in no. 4, 1959
    - Vol. 11, no. 1-3, 1960
    - Vol. 12, no. 1-4. Proceedings in no. 4, 1961
    - Vol. 13, no. 1-3, 1962
    - Vol. 14, no. 1-4 with index. Proceedings in no. 4, 1963
    - Vol. 15, no. 1-4. Proceedings in no. 4, 1964
    - Vol. 16, no. 1-4 with index. Proceedings in no. 4, 1965
    - Vol. 17, no. 1-4. Proceedings in no. 4, 1966
- Box 22, Publications, 1967-2005 (Box 22)
  - Virginia Journal of Science: New Series 1967-2002
    - Vol. 18, no. 1-4, 1967
    - Vol. 19, no. 1, 3-4, 1968
    - Vol. 20, no. 4, 1969
    - Vol. 21, no. 2, 1970
    - None, 1971
    - Vol. 23, no. 3, 1972
    - Vol. 24, no. 1-3, 1973
    - None, 1974
    - Vol. 26, no. 1-2, 4, 1975
    - Vol. 27, no. 2-4, 1976
    - Vol. 28, no. 1-4, 1977
    - Vol. 29, no. 1-4, 1978
    - Vol. 30, no. 1-2, 1979
    - Vol. 31, no. 4, 1980
    - Vol. 32, no. 1-3, 1981
    - Vol. 33, no. 1, 1982
    - Vol. 34, no. 2-3, 1983
    - Vol. 35, no. 3-4, 1984
    - Vol. 36, no. 1-4, 1985
    - Vol. 37, no. 1-4, 1986
    - Vol. 38, no. 1-4, 1987
    - Vol. 39, no. 1-4, 1988
    - Vol. 40, no. 1-4, 1989
    - Vol. 41, no. 1-3, 4A-4B, 1990
    - Vol. 42, no. 1-4 with supplement, 1991
    - Vol. 43, no. 1A-1B, 2-4 with supplement, 1992
    - Vol. 44, no. 1-3 with supplement, 1993
    - None, 1994
    - None, 1995
    - None, 1996
    - None, 1997
    - Vol. 49, no. 1-4, 1998
    - Vol. 50, no. 1-4, 1999
    - Vol. 51, no. 1-4, 2000
    - Vol. 52, no. 2-4, 2001
    - Vol. 53, no. 1-3, 2002
  - Claytonia, 1934-1939
    - Bound volumes 1-2, June 1934-May 1936.
    - Bound volumes 3-5, July 1936-April 1939.
  - Virginia Scientists, 1990-2005
    - Vol. 1, Issue 1, August 1990
    - Vol. 1, Issue 2, November 1990
    - Vol. 1, Issue 3, March 1991
    - Vol. 2, Issue 1, September 1991
    - Vol. 2 Issue 2, November 1991
    - Vol. 2, Issue 3, April 1992
    - Vol. 3, Issue 1, October 1992
    - Vol. 3, Issue 2, February 1993
    - Vol. 3, Issue 3, May 1993
    - Vol. 4, Issue 1, September 1993
    - Vol. 4, Issue 2, January 1994
    - Vol. 4, Issue 3, April 1994
    - Vol. 5, Issue 1, April 1995
    - Vol. 6, Issue 1, April 1996
    - Vol. 7, Issue 1, April 1997
    - Vol. 8, Issue 1, March 1998
    - Vol. 8, Issue 2, May 1998
    - Vol. 9, Issue 1, October-November 1998
    - Vol. 9, Issue 2, February 1999
    - Vol. 9, Issue 3, April 1999
    - Vol. 10, Issue 1, September 1999
    - Vol. 10, Issue 2, January 2000
    - Vol. 10, Issue 3, April 2000
    - Vol. 11, Issue 1, September 2000
    - Vol. 11, Issue 2, February 2001
    - Vol. 11, Issue 3, April 2001
    - Vol. 13, Issue 1, September 2002
    - Vol. 13, Issue 2, January 2003
    - Vol. 13, Issue 3, April 2003
    - Vol. 15, Issue 2, December 2004
    - Vol. 15, Issue 3, April 2005
    - Vol. 16, Issue 1, September-October 2005
- Box 23, Publications, 1940-1972 (Box 23)
  - Virginia Journal of Science: Bound, Vol. 1-3, January 1940-May 1943
  - Virginia Journal of Science; New Series: Bound, 1950-1972
    - Vol. 1-2, 1950-1951
    - Vol. 3-4, 1952-1953
    - Vol. 5-6, 1954-1955
    - Vol. 7-8, 1956-1957
    - Vol. 9-10, 1958-1959
    - Vol. 11-12, 1960-1961
    - Vol. 13-14, 1962-1963
    - Vol. 15-16, 1964-1965
    - Vol. 17, 1966
    - Vol. 18-19, 1967-1968
    - Vol. 20-21, 1969-1970
    - Vol. 22-23, 1971-1972
- Box 24, Publications, 1925-1987 (Box 24)
  - Virginia Academy of Science Programs, 1925-1942, 1944, 1946-1953, 1955-1993, 1995-1997
  - Virginia Academy of Science Directories, Complete run, 1971-1988
  - Virginia Academy of Science Informational Brochures, 1946-1950, 1952-1956, 1958-1971, 1975-1976
  - Virginia Academy of Science List of Members, 1969, 1972
  - Early Virginia
    - Reprint of the Virginia Journal of Science; New Series, Vol. 8, no. 1, January 1957
  - The History of Early Publications of the Virginia Academy of Science
    - The History of the Virginia Journal of Science, and The History of the Virginia Journal of Science, New Series, 1932-1962. Written by Boyd Harshbarger.
- Box 25, Publications, 1923-1950 (Box 25)
  - The James River Basin; Past, Present, and Future
  - The James River Project Committee of the Virginia Academy of Science, Richmond, VA, 1950
  - Virginia Academy of Science Proceedings: Bound
  - Bound Minutes and notes of 1973-74 Committee and Council Meetings.
    - Bound book 1, 1923-1938
    - Bound book 2, 1938-1944
    - Bound book 3, 1944-1949
  - Typesetter's printing block of a photograph from the Virginia Academy of Science in Richmond, VA on May 4, 1925
  - Mrs. George W. Jeffers name tag from the 9th Annual Meeting of the VAS in Norfolk, VA on April 24-25, 1931
- Box 26, Memorabilia, 1994-1996 (Box 26)
  - Photograph album of the 72nd Annual Meeting of the VAS and the 53rd Annual Meeting of the VJAS at James Madison University in Harrisonburg, VA on May 17-20, 1994
  - Photograph album of the 73rd Annual Meeting of the VAS and the 54th Annual Meeting of the VJAS at Virginia Military Institute in Lexington, VA on May 23-26, 1995
  - Photograph album of the 74th Annual Meeting of the VAS and the 55th Annual Meeting of the VJAS at Virginia Commonwealth University in Richmond, VA on May 21-24, 1996
  - Souvenir cup of the VAS and VJAS.
  - Three medals from the VAS and VJAS Annual Meetings.
  - Souvenir T-shirt of the VAS and VJAS.
- Box 27, Bound Publications, 1938-1976 (Box 27)
  - Virginia Academy of Science General Journal, 1938-1970
  - Ledger of Accountants Transactions, 1949-1970
  - Checkbook of VAS Visiting Scientists Program, 1965-1967
  - Checkbook of VAS Research Fund, 1966-1973
  - Ledger of Financial Information, 1968
  - Ledger of Financial Information, 1969
  - Ledger of Financial Information, 1970
  - Checkbook of VAS General Fund, 1970-1971
  - Checkbook of VAS General Fund, 1971-1973
  - Checkbook of VAS General Fund, 1972-1973
  - Copy of VAS Minutes, 1974-1976
- Box 28, Ledgers, 1966-1996 (Box 28)
  - Bound Ledger of Financial Information, 1966-1996
  - Bound Ledger of Financial Information, 1970
- Box 29, Arthur W. Burke Papers, 1973-1975 (Box 29)
  - Executive Committee, 1973
  - Council Meetings, 1973
  - Miscellaneous, 1973-1974
  - Miscellaneous, 1973-1974
  - Gifted and Talented Students, 1973-1974
  - Ragone and Stanley--Presidential Correspondence, 1973-1974
  - Council Meetings, 1974
  - Long Range Planning Committee, 1974
  - Executive Committee, 1974
  - Math teacher’s certification, 1974
  - Council list, 1974
  - VAS Awards, 1974
  - VAS Finance Reports, 1974-1975
  - Annual Meeting, 1974-1975
  - Local Arrangements Committee, 1974-1975
  - VJAS Correspondence, 1974-1975
  - Miscellaneous, 1974-1977
  - Virginia State Science Teachers Conference, 1975
  - VAS Meeting--Miscellaneous, 1975
  - Tree and Friends of Africa in America, 1975
- Box 30, Arthur W. Burke Papers, 1975-1978 (Box 30)
  - Council Meetings, 1975
  - New Committee Appointments, 1975
  - Program--Correspondence, 1975
  - VJAS Meeting, 1975
  - VAS Council Meeting, 1976
  - List of invited guests to a VAS meeting, 1976
  - Annual Meeting--Thank you letters, 1976
  - VAS Budget presentation to AAAS, 1976
  - VAS Meeting, 1976
  - VAS Academy Conference, 1976
  - Virginia Journal of Science Guest Editorial, 1976
  - Virginia Journal of Science, 1976-1977
  - Council Meetings, 1977
  - Annual Meeting, 1978
  - Council Meetings, 1978
  - VAS Science Advisors, 1978
  - Miscellaneous, 1978
  - Virginia Journal of Science--Kuldip A. Chopra, 1978
- Box 31, Donald G. Cochran Papers, 1971-1980 (Box 31)
  - VAS Meeting of the Local Arrangements Committee, 1971
  - VAS Meetings--Miscellaneous, 1973-1976
  - VJAS Committee, 1975
  - VJAS Meeting, 1976
  - VJAS Meeting, 1977
  - Meeting of the Local Arrangements Committee (2 folders), 1978
  - VAS Financial Records, 1978
  - VAS Executive Committee (4 folders), 1978-1979
  - Programs of VAS meetings, 1978-1979
  - Executive Meetings--Minutes, 1979-1980
  - VAS Meeting--Minutes (2 folders), 1980
- Box 32, Boyd Harshbarger Papers, 1957-1969 (Box 32)
  - "Training Program in Biometry"--Written by Harshbarger, 1957-1958
  - VAS Miscellaneous, 1960-1962
  - VAS Miscellaneous, 1960-1967
  - Finance and Endowment Committee (2 folders), 1961-1962
  - VAS Council Meeting, November 3, 1962
  - Scientific Manpower Survey in Virginia, 1962
  - VAS Annual Meeting, May 9-11, 1962
  - Horsley Research Awards, 1962